[](https://www.klove.com/)[](https://www.klove.com/search)Open main menu

* Music
    
    Faith
    
    DJs

    Contests
    
    Events
    
    News
    
    About Us
    
* Sign in

* [Loading...  
    Loading...](#)
* Listen At: Change
    
    Loading...

* 

Privacy Policy
==============

**PRIVACY POLICY**

Welcome to the Educational Media Foundation Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy governs the activities of all affiliates and brands of Educational Media Foundation ("EMF", "we" or "us"). Educational Media Foundation is a California non-profit religious organization operating Christian media ministries under the brands K-LOVE, Air1, AccessMore, WTA Media, Crisis Response Care, Air1’s Dare to Dream, Pray4One and more, and to their respective Sites and mobile applications (collectively, the "Sites"). We are committed to the protection of your personal information. This Privacy Policy sets out the basis on which we collect and use personal information about you as part of our ministry activities and the choices you have to limit or prevent certain uses or sharing of that information. This Privacy Policy applies to our Sites, mobile applications, pastoral care services, prayer requests (including our Pray4One application), live events, contests and other products and services, all of which we call “Services” in this Privacy Policy. Please note that this Privacy Policy does not govern the Sites and services of third parties that may link to or be accessed from This or our other Sites or applications.  If you donate to us, please see our [Donor Privacy Policy](https://www.klove.com/policies/donor-privacy-policy) about how we handle your sensitive payment information. 

**Information We Collect About You**

We may collect information, including your name, address, email address, and phone number when you communicate with us or sign up for one of our Services. You also may provide additional information to us such as your birthdate, content preferences, communication content or payment information. We also gather information about how visitors navigate our Sites by using data gathered with cookies. This type of information is collected automatically and includes the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; login; e-mail address; passwords used for our Sites; computer and connection information such as browser type and version, operating system, and platform; the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) clickstream to, through, and from our Site(s), including date and time; cookie number; and Services that you viewed or searched for. If you send us a review, post content on our social media sites, or respond to a survey, we collect your submission content. We may also obtain information about you from our third party partners, such as if you create a Pray4One account through your Facebook account, we’ll receive information from that service (e.g., your username, basic profile information, friends list) via the authorization procedures for that service, and from other partners who may provide us publicly available and other information they have collected about you. Through our arrangements with our social media and advertising partners, when you visit your social media pages (such as Facebook or Instagram), we may collect personal information from or about you from those sites. 

**Sources of Information We Collect**

We collect information directly from individuals, automatically related to the use of our Services, and in some cases from third parties (such as advertising networks, internet service providers, operating systems and platforms, and social media platforms). For example, we collect information:

* from any form you may complete and submit through our Sites, for example, information collected from the "Contact Us" page of our Sites;
* from the content of surveys that you may complete;
* from 'cookies' and other similar tools deployed on parts of our Sites;
* when you provide information when you subscribe and in connection with us providing services to you;
* from other sources, such as advertising and marketing partners, social media platforms (including from people with whom you are friends or otherwise connected), internet service providers, and operating systems and platforms.

**How We Collect Your Information**

As noted above, we collect information that you voluntarily provide to us when you interact with us or our Services – such as when you sign up for a K-LOVE or Air1 newsletter or Verse of the Day subscription; register to use any of our Services; sign-up for a contest; participate in an online survey emailed to you; visit our booth at a local event; phone into our Audience Engagement line; or speak with an EMF Pastor or other member of our prayer or Pastoral Care Team. Direct collection may take place online, in person or over the phone with an EMF employee or third party call center agent We may get personal information about you from social media services online if you sign up for any of our Services using your social media account (such as Facebook, Instagram, or Pinterest) or from third party partner concert promotors or cruise line operators when you sign up for concert tickets or to take a cruise. Additionally, we and our third-party analytics partners collect personal information about you when you visit us through the web or your mobile device via cookies, pixels, and similar tracking technologies. This personal information includes information about your online activities over time and across different Services. Please see the section below on “Cookies”.

**How We Use Your Information**

We may use or disclose your personal information that we collect for one or more of the following business purposes:

* Providing and Improving our Services. To provide, maintain, improve, and enhance our services, and to facilitate transactions and payments.
* Tailoring Content. To personalize your experience with our Services, such as by providing tailored content and recommendations.
* Research and Analytics. To better understand how you use our Services, to evaluate and improve our Services and business operations, and to develop new Services.
* Marketing and Advertising. For marketing and advertising purposes, such as developing promotional and advertising materials that may be relevant, valuable, or interesting and then delivering those materials to you.
* Communications. To communicate with you, provide you with updates and other information relating to our Services, provide information that you request, respond to your comments and questions, and otherwise provide customer support.
* De-identification and aggregation. To de-identify personal information or create aggregated datasets, such as for consolidating reporting, research, or analysis.
* General Business Operations. To support our general business operations, including for corporate audit, analysis, and reporting.
* Legal Compliance. To comply with applicable legal or regulatory obligations, including as part of a judicial proceeding. To respond to a subpoena, warrant, court order, or other legal process. Or, as part of an investigation or request, whether formal or informal, from law enforcement or a governmental authority.
* Protecting Rights and Interests. To protect the safety, property, or security of our Sites, our business operations and Services, or the general public. To investigate, detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues. To investigate, prevent or stop activity that EMF, in its sole discretion, may consider to be or appears to pose the risk of being an illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity. To use as evidence in litigation, conduct audits, and to enforce this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use for our Services. To manage or respond to actual and potential legal disputes and claims, and to otherwise establish, defend, or protect our rights or interests, including in the context of anticipated or actual litigation with third parties.
* Protecting Us and Others. To investigate, prevent, or take action to guard against illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, or violations of our Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy, or as evidence in litigation in which we are involved.

**Information We Share**

We may share some of your personal information with third parties for business reasons, as outlined below: 

* Affiliates. We may disclose certain personal information we collect about you to our affiliates (e.g., our subsidiaries and entities under common ownership with EMF) to complete the performance of Services or related transactions.
* Third Party Vendors and Service Providers. Like many businesses, we sometimes engage other companies to perform certain business-related functions for us, such as consulting, service processing and the like (“Vendors” or “Service Providers”).Examples of such functions include mailing, emailing and texting communications to you, maintaining our databases, and processing payments.When we employ another entity to perform a function of this nature, we only provide them with the personal information that they need to perform their specific function.
* Analytics Partners. As noted above (“How We Collect Your Information - Automatic Browser Collection”), we may use third-party online tracking and analytic services (such as Google Analytics, Facebook, or others) and share certain personal information with them to help us understand how you use our Services and how to improve upon your experience with those Services. Each such third-party’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policy.Please see our “Cookies” section below for more information.
* Advertising Partners. We work with online third-party advertising partners to present special ads we think may interest you when you visit our sites or visit the sites of Third Parties, including Facebook and other social media networks. We do this through the use of remarketing tracking Tags. We also may use custom audiences based on emails addresses and phone numbers of our subscribers and Site visitors. This allows us to present special offers for our products and services to you via Facebook and Google. We may also share your personal information with third-party advertising partners for their marketing, research, or similar purposes. Please see “Cookies,” below, to learn about your options regarding personalized ads.
* Business Transfer Partners. If (i) we or our affiliates are acquired by, merged with, or invested in by another company, or (ii) if any of our assets are transferred to another company, whether as part of a bankruptcy or insolvency proceeding or otherwise, we may transfer the information collected from you to the other company.As part of the business transfer process, we may share certain pieces of your personal information with lenders, auditors, attorneys, consultants, and other third-party advisors.
* Parties to Legal Action. We may disclose your personal information to comply with the law, a judicial proceeding, court order, subpoena, or other legal process.
* Please note that we may also disclose your personal information where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use or this Policy, or where it is reasonably necessary as evidence in litigation in which we are involved.

**Cookies**

As mentioned above, when you visit us on our Sites or use one of our mobile applications, we collect information about you by using cookies, pixels, and other tracking technologies, which we may combine with other personal information we collect about you. Some examples of the data we collect from cookies and similar technologies include your account preferences, pages accessed, language preferences, and previous visits to our websites. We use this information to better understand, customize, and improve your experience using our Services, as well as to manage our advertising. For example, we use third-party analytics and advertising partners' automated devices and applications, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate usage of our Sites. We use these tools to help us improve the performance of our Site and our users’ experience on our Site. 

These third party entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies to perform their services for us. To learn more about Google’s privacy practices, please review the [Google Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). You can also [download the Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) to prevent your data from being used by Google Analytics.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to control whether you will accept cookies, reject cookies, or to notify you each time a certain type cookie is sent to your browser. You may also disable certain third party tracking cookies that we use on our Sites when our sharing of your personal information constitutes a "sale", as further described under the California Privacy Notice, below. Please note that, if you disable cookies on our Sites, some functionality of the Sites will be lost. 

Currently, our systems do not recognize browser “do-not-track” signals.

**Ad Network.** We use network advertisers to serve advertisements on non-affiliated websites or other media (e.g., social networking platforms). This enables us and these network advertisers to target advertisements to you for products and services in which you might be interested. Ad network providers, advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may use cookies, JavaScript, pixels, LSOs and other tracking technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. These cookies and other technologies are governed by each entity's specific privacy policy, not this one. We may provide these advertisers with information, including personal information, about you.

Users may opt out of many ad networks. For example, you may go to the Digital Advertising Alliance ("DAA") [Consumer Choice Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and their choices regarding having information used by [DAA companies](http://www.aboutads.info/participating/). You may also go to the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI") [Consumer Opt-Out Page](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1) for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and their choices regarding having information used by [NAI members](http://www.networkadvertising.org/participating-networks).

Opting out from one or more companies listed on the DAA [Consumer Choice Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) or the NAI [Consumer Opt-Out Page](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1) will opt you out from those companies' delivery of interest-based content or ads to you, but it does not mean you will no longer receive any advertising through our website or on other websites. You may continue to receive advertisements, for example, based on the particular website that you are viewing (i.e., contextually based ads). Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you opt out on the DAA or NAI websites, your opt out may not be effective. Additional information is available on the DAA's website at [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) or the NAI's website at  [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

**Children**

Children under age 13 (minors) always should get permission from a parent or guardian before providing any personal information about themselves. However, sometimes minors contact us to make a donation, seek a prayer, or request pastoral counseling, or they may interact with us at a Dare to Dream school assembly program or attend a cruise or event, from which we may collect their personal information. If you are a parent of a child under the age of 13, you may contact us at the Contact Information below, to request the information about your child that we have collected or request that we delete such information.

**International Usage of Our Services**

We are based in the U.S., and the personal information we collect is governed by U.S. law. If you are accessing our Services from outside of the U.S., please be aware that personal information collected through our Services may be transferred to, processed, stored, or used in the United States. Data protection laws of the U.S. are likely different from those of your country of residence.

**Security of Your Information**

We are committed to protecting your personal information. We have implemented reasonable precautions to protect the personal information we collect from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Please be aware that despite our best efforts, no data security measures can guarantee absolute security.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of the date stated at the bottom of this document. We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, so please be sure to check back periodically. We will post any changes to this Privacy Policy via our Services.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have questions about our Services with respect to this Privacy Policy, or would like to make a complaint, please contact us in one of the following ways:

1. Email us at [privacy@kloveair1.com](mailto:privacy@kloveair1.com)
2. Use the Contact Us form on this Site
3. US Mail – Educational Media Foundation, 5700 West Oaks Boulevard, Rocklin, CA95765
4. Toll Free Number – (800) 525-5683

**PRIVACY NOTICE FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS**

We are providing this **Privacy Notice for California Residents** ("Notice") pursuant to the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA"). Notice supplements our Privacy Policy.  Capitalized terms used in this Notice but not defined shall have the meaning given to them in the CCPA. 

Categories of Personal Information We Collect

We have collected the following CCPA categories of personal information within the past 12 months (and we have disclosed information within each of these categories to our third party partners and others within the past months, as detailed in the section on "Disclosures and Sales of Personal Information", below):

_Name, Contact Information, and Other Identifiers_ such as a real name, alias, postal address, telephone or mobile contact number, unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address and account name.

_Customer Records_ such as name, contact information, education, employment, employment history and financial information.

_Commercial Information_ such as transaction information, purchase history, financial details and payment information.

_Usage Data_ including internet or other electronic network activity information, such as browsing history, search history, online behavior, interest data, and interactions with our Sites and other websites, applications, systems and advertisements.

_Geolocation data_ such as device location.

_Audio, electronic, visual and similar information_ such as images and audio, video or call recordings created in connection with our business activities.

_Professional or employment-related information_ such as job title as well as work history and experience.

_Protected classifications_ under California or federal law, such as gender and date of birth.

_Inferences and profiles_ drawn from any of the personal information listed above to create a profile or summary about, for example, an individual’s preferences and characteristics.

Sources of Personal Information

We collect the categories of personal information identified above from the sources listed in the “How We Collect Your Information” section of our Privacy Policy, above.

Disclosures and Sales of Personal Information

We have disclosed each of the above-listed categories of personal information for a business purpose within the last 12 months to various third party entities (such as to companies that provide services to us, including our affiliates and subsidiaries, advertising networks, data analytics providers, social networks, internet service providers, operating systems and platforms, or where we are required by law to do so)(For more information about the business or commercial purposes for which we may disclose such information and the categories of third parties to which we may disclose such information, see the “Information We Share” section of our Privacy Policy, above.)

Under the CCPA, a “sale” includes disclosing or making available personal information to a third party in exchange for monetary compensation or other benefits or value.  While we do not disclose personal information to third parties in exchange for monetary compensation, we may disclose or make available certain categories of personal information to third parties in order to receive certain benefits or services, such as when we make browsing information available to third party ad companies (through third party tags on our Sites) in order to improve and measure our ad campaigns and reach users with more relevant ads and content.

As defined by the CCPA, we may “sell” certain categories of personal information as follows:

* Identifiers to third party advertising networks, data analytics providers and other entities that may perform services for us
* Usage Data to third party advertising networks and data analytics providers
* Customer Records to data brokers

To Exercise Your Consumer Privacy Rights

Subject to certain exceptions, under the CCPA, consumers have the right to request information from us about the personal information we collect about them.  Although the CCPA only gives California residents the right to make these requests, we allow non-California residents with the same choices about their personal information. You may make any of the following requests about our collection, use and sharing of your personal information:

* _Requests for Access to Information._ You may request a copy of the specific personal information or the categories of information that we collected about you during the past 12 months and information about how we have collected, used, and shared your personal information during the past 12 months. This includes the categories of personal information collected; categories of sources of personal information; categories of personal information we have disclosed or shared with a third party for a business purpose; categories of third parties to whom we have sold their personal information and, for each, the specific categories of personal information sold; and the business or commercial purposes for collecting or selling personal information.
* _Deletion Requests._ You may ask us to delete the personal information that we collected or maintain about you, with certain exceptions (detailed below).
* _Do-Not-Sell Requests._ You may ask us not to sell your personal information by submitting a consumer privacy request as per below. You also may opt-out of certain third party cookies on our Sites/mobile applications (as described more fully in the "Cookies" section in our Privacy Policy above) by adjusting your browser settings to remove or reject such cookies.

_Non-discrimination._ Consumers also have the right not to be subject to discriminatory treatment for exercising their privacy rights. This means, for example, that when a consumer exercises their consumer privacy rights, we will not deny the consumer any goods or services or provide them with a different level or quality of goods or services.

Submitting Consumer Privacy Rights Requests

To exercise your consumer privacy rights as stated above, you may submit a request to us, as follows:

\-- Online using our [Privacy Rights Request Form](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/eb6dd323-c1d2-4565-bd52-1aa8f0c66ab1)

\-- Emailing us at privacy@kloveair1.com

\-- Calling us toll-free at (800) 525-5683.

In order to submit a consumer privacy rights request, you will need to provide us with the following identifying information so that we may process your request: your name, your mailing address, your telephone number, and your email address.  We will need to verify your identity before we can provide a substantive response to your request. Only you, or an authorized agent that you authorize to act on your behalf, may make a consumer privacy rights request related to your personal information. You may also make a request on behalf of your minor child. 

In order to verify your request, we ask that you:

* Provide sufficient information that allows us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom we collected personal information or an authorized agent who is properly registered and has been authorized in writing by the consumer whose personal information is being requested (we will ask authorized agents to provide the consumer's written authorization for confirmation).
* Describe your request with sufficient detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to it.

We cannot respond to your request or provide you with personal information if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm the personal information relates to you. Making a verifiable consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. We will only use personal information provided in a verifiable consumer request to verify the requestor's identity or authority to make the request.

Exceptions to Consumer Privacy Rights Requests.

In certain circumstances we may decline your consumer privacy rights request, such as where fulfilling a request may interfere with a transaction you have asked us to process for you or to comply with other obligations under other applicable laws. If we deny your request, we will communicate our decision to you. We will not penalize you for making a request.

**Changes to Our Privacy Notice**

We reserve the right to amend this privacy notice and other notices at our discretion and at any time, including updating regarding our data practices and your rights, modify our methods for responding to your requests, and/or supplement our response to your requests. When we make changes to this privacy notice, we will notify you by email or through a notice on our Sites' homepages.

**Rev. November 2021**

Get exclusive music and faith content and enter contests with our weekly email!

Sign Up

* K-LOVE App

* K-LOVE Apps

* Popular Links

* Help
* Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information

* Faith

* About Us

K-LOVE is a ministry of Educational Media Foundation, a not for profit 501(c)(3) organization (taxpayer ID Number: 94-2816342). Gifts are tax deductible to the extent allowed by U.S. federal and state tax laws.

© 2024 Educational Media Foundation, All rights reserved
